# Konstantin Tenman

Software Engineer London, United Kingdom

+447487553781konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

#### PROFILE

Self-motivated Software Developer with six years of experience including over five years of experience in Java development. I would like to participate in true teamwork and develop well-tested applications using a continuous delivery approach. I enjoy doing deep investigations, learning new technologies, and always looking for ways to do things better.

## Programming Skills

• Languages: Java 8+, TypeScript **Technologies:** Spring Boot, Angular 2+, Hibernate, Junit, Mockito

• Tools: Docker, PostgreSQL, AWS, Redis, Git, Jenkins, Maven, macOS, IntelliJ, SNS/SQS

#### EXPERIENCE

• Monese London, United Kingdom Mar 2019 - Present Software Engineer

• Reduced costs by systematically working to improve software performance and decrease their operating costs. For

- one application, it's monthly operating cost was decreased by 50%.
- o Increased revenue by doggedly identifying and fixing production issues. In one case, pursuing a fix for a single customer led to identifying a significant gap in profit.
- o Pricing: Researched regarding breaking monolithic responsibility micro-services. Refactored and developed the pricing structure of the system. Delivered business priorities by completing new annual pricing functionality on-time and without any significant issues.
- Joint Accounts: Designed and developed the main logic around the Joint Accounts.

 Monese Tallinn, Estonia Software Engineer Oct 2017 - Mar 2019

- Smart Transactions: Improved scalability of micro-services by separating read and write operation of the database. Migrated gradually 120M payments to new queue-based Java micro-service. Decreased average response time from 60ms to 5ms. Researched and introduced the new Angular 5 framework for internal tooling. Helped to improve seamless deployment in Amazon AWS.
- Recurring Payments: Designe and developed a micro-service with test coverage of up to 80%.
- o Tools: Java 8-11, Angular, TypeScript, Grails, Scala, Docker, Amazon AWS, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, Google API, Mockito, Junit, Redis, AWS, CloudWatch, New Relic, Jenkins, Git, Intellij, Groovy, Testcontainers, Maven, Liquibase, Bootstrap, macOS

• Codeborne Tallinn, Estonia

Apr 2017 - Oct 2017 Software Developer

- Bank Saint-Petersburg: Developed internet banking website which is used by 2M customers and mobile application.
- Czech Expobank: Developed a responsive internet banking website for desktop and mobile platforms.
- o Tools: Java 8, RiotJS, Selenium, Mockito, TDD, Intellij, Agile, extreme programming, Play! Framework, Ubuntu

• Knowit Tallinn, Estonia

Jun 2016 - Apr 2017 Software Developer

- Developed a full-stack web-based application where users create services and search for them through Google Maps.
- Technologies: AngularJS, Java 8, Docker, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JHipster, Sass, CSS3, HTML5, Protractor, Maven, Liquibase, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Ubuntu, Git

### EDUCATION

• Tallinn University Estonia